<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Dev Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-30T20:14:03-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ilteris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ilteris kaplan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Block Objects in iOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/11/25/block-objects-in-ios/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-25T10:22:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/11/25/block-objects-in-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“Block objects can either be inline or coded as independent blocks of code.
Let’s start with the latter type. Suppose you have a method in Objective-C that
accepts two integer values of type NSInteger and returns the difference of the
two values, by subtracting one from the other, as an NSInteger:”</p>

<pre><code>- (NSInteger) subtract:(NSInteger)paramValue from:(NSInteger)paramFrom { 
return paramFrom - paramValue;
}
</code></pre>

<p>pure C function that provides the same functionality to get one step closer to
learning the syntax of block objects:</p>

<pre><code>NSInteger subtract(NSInteger paramValue, NSInteger paramFrom){
    return paramFrom - paramValue;
    }
</code></pre>

<p>You can see that the C function is quite different in syntax from its
Objective-C counterpart. Now let’s have a look at how we could code the same
function as a block object:</p>

<pre><code>NSInteger (^subtract)(NSInteger, NSInteger) = ^(NSInteger paramValue,
    NSInteger paramFrom) {        
            return paramFrom - paramValue;
                };
</code></pre>

<p>Suppose we have a function in C that takes a parameter of type NSUInteger (an
unsigned integer) and returns it as a string of type NSString. Here is how we implement this in C:</p>

<pre><code>NSString* intToString (NSUInteger paramInteger){

    return [NSString stringWithFormat:@"%lu",
                (unsigned long)paramInteger];
                    }
</code></pre>

<p>The block object equivalent of this C function is:</p>

<pre><code>NSString* (^intToString)(NSUInteger) = ^(NSUInteger paramInteger){

    NSString *result = [NSString stringWithFormat:@"%lu",
                            (unsigned long)paramInteger];

                                    return result;
};
</code></pre>

<p>The simplest form of an independent block object would be a block object that
returns void and does  not take in any parameters:</p>

<pre><code>void (^simpleBlock)(void) = ^{
/* Implement the block object here */

};
</code></pre>

<p>Block objects can be invoked in the exact same way as C functions. If they have
any parameters, you pass those as you would for a C function, and any return
value can be retrieved exactly as you would retrieve a C function’s return
value. Here is an example:”</p>

<pre><code>NSString* (^intToString)(NSUInteger) = ^(NSUInteger paramInteger){

    NSString *result = [NSString stringWithFormat:@"%lu",
                            (unsigned long)paramInteger];

                                    return result;


};

- (void) callIntToString{

    NSString *string = intToString(10);
        NSLog(@"string = %@", string);
</code></pre>

<p>   }</p>

<p>“The callIntToString Objective-C method is calling the intToString block object
by passing the value 10 as the only parameter to this block object and placing
the return value of this block object in the string local variable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dash for Offline API Reading]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/11/23/dash-for-offline-api-reading/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-23T10:54:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/11/23/dash-for-offline-api-reading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kapeli.com/dash">Dash</a> is a great tool for reading documentation offline
of your favorite framework or library. You can also generate <a href="http://kapeli.com/docsets">your own docsets</a> and host them as feeds so anyone can use it.
I have found an open source iOS project on github (<a href="https://github.com/omz/DocSets-for-iOS">https://github.com/omz/DocSets-for-iOS</a>) for reading the mac os x / iOS docsets
which is a bit dated but have not been able to find any project that&rsquo;s
compatible with Dash docsets in general. Maybe a side project?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parse and Facebook Integration for iOS and Ideas]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/30/parse-and-facebook-integration-for-ios-and-ideas/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-30T21:09:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/30/parse-and-facebook-integration-for-ios-and-ideas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Log in facebook in parse allows for read permissions. This doesn&rsquo;t require to
launch facebook app. Simple popup allows this. Instead does everything in the
background. We can pull fb user&rsquo;s id, name etc. with this. We can then link this
to PFuser object in our User table.  Parse allows devellopers to store and link
uploaded photos by users on Parse. This opens up freedom to create applications
to have linked users (by facebook) on Parse.
One scenario:</p>

<pre><code>            User A logs in with facebook on app X. App X grabs all of his fb
            friend list and save it to Parse. Then, his friend user B logs
            in with facebook using app X. This gives us possibility to send
            a notification to the user A saying, your friend just joined the
            app. 
</code></pre>

<p>Birthdays:</p>

<pre><code>      Login with facebook, your friends birthday and get automatic
      notification to your phone.
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mavericks YouCompleteMe]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/29/mavericks-youcompleteme/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-29T19:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/29/mavericks-youcompleteme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you start getting lots of errors on your YCM plugin for vim, it&rsquo;s most likely
using 10.9. What you need to do is to compile your vim on 10.9. If you are lazy,
go grab macvim and just copy the mvim script that&rsquo;s in the package to your
/usr/local/bin dir. Delete the old vim binary and just create a symlink [ ln -s
/usr/local/bin/mvim /usr/local/bin/vim] and you are good to go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alcatraz for Xcode]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/25/alcatraz-for-xcode/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-25T10:32:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/25/alcatraz-for-xcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://mneorr.github.io/Alcatraz/">Alcatraz</a> is a nifty package manager tool for Xcode. I stumbled upon it when I
was reading Jack Chen&rsquo;s <a href="https://github.com/chendo/FuzzyAutocompletePlugin">fuzzy matching code completion
plugin.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Vim More Useful]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/13/making-vim-more-useful/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-13T15:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/13/making-vim-more-useful</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To make vim more useful and act like bit like emacs, it&rsquo;s possible to install
this plugin called <a href="https://github.com/teranex/tslime.vim">tslime.vim</a>. I have
tried official slime but unfortunately that created a lot of problems with tmux.
This is the only fork that worked on multiple windows multiple panes setup. Once
installed (I use pathogen to install it but you can use whatever you want) you
can use <c c> <c c> to teleport the code to the node that&rsquo;s running in another
pane. It&rsquo;s quite useful.</p>

<p>Another useful plugin is
<a href="https://github.com/Valloric/YouCompleteMe">YouCompleteMe</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/SirVer/ultisnips">ultisnips</a>. Unfortunately it&rsquo;s not
seamless but it definitely gets the job done. It allows you to choose the
dropdown snippets and allow you to choose those using <c j> and then going
forward/back using <c j> and <c k> in the placeholder variables. There&rsquo;s an
issue that&rsquo;s stated on the github that promises to fix the problem but
unfortunately it doesn&rsquo;t work for vim that runs in the terminal. For it to work
probably one needs macvim.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/marijnh/tern_for_vim">Tern for vim</a> is another useful
pluging for doing javascript in vim. For me beside the killer feature is to
allow me to jump to defition of functions. Follow the installation instructions
and then whenever cursor is on a variable or a property TernDef takes you there.
I have just started using it so, at this point scratching the surface. Another
handy vim command <code>&lt;c o &gt;</code> and <code>&lt;c i&gt;</code> allows to go jumpback to old cursor
positions if one wants to go back.</p>

<p>These are all useful additions to vim workspace.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Crouton on Samsung ChromeBook]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/installing-crouton-on-samsung-chromebook/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T13:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/installing-crouton-on-samsung-chromebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am considering getting a cheap laptop and turn that into a developer machine.
I don&rsquo;t like using MBP when I am in the bed being the main excuse. It looks like
Crouton is the way to go for hacking the Chromebook into a debian machine. Only
downside is Samsung ChromeBook is ARM based, which means it&rsquo;s not possible to
run binaries that are not compiled for ARMs.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.howtogeek.com/162120/how-to-install-ubuntu-linux-on-your-chromebook-with-crouton/">http://www.howtogeek.com/162120/how-to-install-ubuntu-linux-on-your-chromebook-with-crouton/</a></p>

<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6499625">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6499625</a></p>

<p><a href="http://pclosmag.com/html/Issues/201109/page08.html">http://pclosmag.com/html/Issues/201109/page08.html</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Javascript Dependency Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/javascript-dependency-management/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-02T09:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/javascript-dependency-management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unlike many other languages javascript doesn&rsquo;t have a standard way to import
modules. This made people to come up with different solutions like CommonJS, AMD
or using plain old global namespace. It took me a while to understand what&rsquo;s
going on with the whole dependency management eco-system and what they mean and
how they work.</p>

<p>Here are a few webpages to grasp it better:</p>

<p><a href="http://yahooeng.tumblr.com/post/62383009835/javascript-modules-amd-and-the-road-ahead">http://yahooeng.tumblr.com/post/62383009835/javascript-modules-amd-and-the-road-ahead</a></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.startifact.com/posts/overwhelmed-by-javascript-dependencies.html">http://blog.startifact.com/posts/overwhelmed-by-javascript-dependencies.html</a></p>

<p><a href="http://blog.testdouble.com/posts/2013-06-16-unrequired-love.html">http://blog.testdouble.com/posts/2013-06-16-unrequired-love.html</a></p>

<p><a href="http://dontkry.com/posts/code/browserify-and-the-universal-module-definition.html">http://dontkry.com/posts/code/browserify-and-the-universal-module-definition.html</a></p>

<p>Generally there are two camps, RequireJS and CommonJS. CommonJS is similar to
how npm but AMD people (RequireJS) think it&rsquo;s a javascript hack and it doesn&rsquo;t
conform to the standards. From the other side, the critization is, RequireJS
adds a lot of headache when project gets bigger.</p>

<p>It looks like with ECMAScript 6, Javascript folks are going to try to come up
with a cleaner and more important standard way of handling all these tasks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy Paste on Tmux on Mac Os X]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/copy-paste-on-tmux-on-mac-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T19:22:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/copy-paste-on-tmux-on-mac-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you ever find yourself working with two different instances of vim under mac
os x using tmux, copy/paste will not work like you expect it to work. Go to
<a href="https://github.com/ChrisJohnsen/tmux-MacOSX-pasteboard">https://github.com/ChrisJohnsen/tmux-MacOSX-pasteboard</a> and read more about it.
Once you follow the instructions, then it works flawlessly. My love/hate
relationship with tmux continues.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tabs Outliner]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/tabs-outliner/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T16:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/27/tabs-outliner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have found a great Chrome extension, tab outliner
<a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tabs-outliner/eggkanocgddhmamlbiijnphhppkpkmkl?hl=en,">https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/tabs-outliner/eggkanocgddhmamlbiijnphhppkpkmkl?hl=en,</a>
it allows one to keep tabs to minimum by allowing to save them in an tree
interface. For a peace of mind, it&rsquo;s essential.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[App Annie Analytics]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/app-annie-analytics/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-23T17:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/app-annie-analytics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a handy website that allows one to check out different app stores top
games list. It definitely gives an insight about what people buy across the
globe.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s one for Turkey:
<a href="http://www.appannie.com/top/iphone/turkey/">http://www.appannie.com/top/iphone/turkey/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scrapbook]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/scrapbook/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T13:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/scrapbook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another app idea of mine is codename scrapbook. Often times, I find myself browsing through all kinds of webpages, PDFs, videos when I am trying to learn a new language, framework or technology. Things get out of hand pretty quickly. It becomes hard to follow and remember where I leave things off, when I want to pick up later. Browser often becomes a mess with 120 tabs open.</p>

<p>In order to solve this problem it will be good to have a service where it&rsquo;s easy to dump links, text, video, in order to pick those up later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chartist App]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/chartist/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T11:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/chartist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a project I have been thinking about for a while. I envisioned it as a service for my own needs when I want to be able save charts along with typical information like entry, exit points to look at them later.</p>

<p>For a very simple start, I need a few things to make this work:
1. Figure out a way to route the screen shot of the chart from desktop using mac os x screenshot application to the chartist application.
2. Get a few inputs from the user including the derivative symbol, entry price, exit price.
3. Try to grab the feed from the yahoo finance API.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Markdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/markdown/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/markdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a simple interactive tutorial that gives the basics on markdown. (<a href="http://www.markdowntutorial.com/">http://www.markdowntutorial.com/</a>) Octopress is based on markdown by default, so it&rsquo;s useful to learn it before going forward.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress Zsh Madness]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/09/octopress-zsh-madness/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-09T18:27:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/09/octopress-zsh-madness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I cannot believe I spent 3 hours on octopress installation. I deleted the repository 5 times and try to re-install only to find out that all problems were related to zsh. Basically don&rsquo;t bother installing octopress on zsh. Just change the shell to bash and go ahead. It won&rsquo;t take more than 5 minutes.
<a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/117">https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/117</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/09/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-09T18:13:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/09/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the hello world post. Testing editing too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
