<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ideas | Dev Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/categories/ideas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T23:16:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://ilteris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ilteris kaplan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scrapbook]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/scrapbook/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T13:12:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/scrapbook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another app idea of mine is codename scrapbook. Often times, I find myself browsing through all kinds of webpages, PDFs, videos when I am trying to learn a new language, framework or technology. Things get out of hand pretty quickly. It becomes hard to follow and remember where I leave things off, when I want to pick up later. Browser often becomes a mess with 120 tabs open.</p>

<p>In order to solve this problem it will be good to have a service where it&rsquo;s easy to dump links, text, video, in order to pick those up later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chartist App]]></title>
    <link href="http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/chartist/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T11:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ilteris.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/chartist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a project I have been thinking about for a while. I envisioned it as a service for my own needs when I want to be able save charts along with typical information like entry, exit points to look at them later.</p>

<p>For a very simple start, I need a few things to make this work:
1. Figure out a way to route the screen shot of the chart from desktop using mac os x screenshot application to the chartist application.
2. Get a few inputs from the user including the derivative symbol, entry price, exit price.
3. Try to grab the feed from the yahoo finance API.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
